<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<task id="createPlanWithDeletedAndPerPlan">
  <title>Deleted and Per Plan Projects</title>
  <taskbody>
    <context>
      <p>
        A deleted project within the Capacity Planner is a project that is currently in use in a pod but you wish to plan its removal.
        A per plan project within the Capacity Planner is a project that has been planned to be removed from one pod and moved to another.
      </p>
      <p><b>Objective</b></p>
      <p>Use the Capacity Planner to create or update a plan with deleted projects and per plan projects for efficient cloud resource allocation</p>
      <p>
        <b>Outline</b>
        <ol>
          <li><xref href="#openPlan">Open the Plan View</xref></li>
          <li><xref href="#deleteAProject">Delete a Project from a Cloud Pod</xref></li>
          <li><xref href="#perPlanProject">Reassign a deleted project</xref></li>
        </ol>
      </p>
    </context>
    <prereq>
      <p>To create or update a plan successfully the user must have the following:</p>
      <ul>
        <li>Relevant Cloud Pods already created in the tool</li>
        <li>Relevant Projects already created in the tool</li>
        <li>Relevant Deployment Types already created in the tool</li>
        <li>Relevant Teams already created in the tool</li>
      </ul>
    </prereq>
    <steps>
      <step id="openPlan">
        <cmd>Open the Create Plan View</cmd>
        <info>
          <p>Click the <b>Create new plan</b> button from the plans page or click on the plan you wish to edit.</p>
        </info>
      </step>
      <step id="deleteAProject">
        <cmd>Delete a Project from a Cloud Pod</cmd>
        <info>
          <p>Click the <b>X</b> button on the project you wish to delete
            When you click the button the project will become grey and the
            <b>X</b> button will change to a <b>+</b> which will allow the project to be re-added to the plan.
            This deleted project will be added to the per plan project list below the backlog prokect list.
            The project can be re-added using this list.
          </p>
        </info>
      </step>
      <step id="perPlanProject">
        <cmd>Reassign a deleted project</cmd>
        <info>
          <p>
            Navigate to the pod you wish to add a project to.
            From the per plan project list select the project you want to add.
            When selected press the <b>+</b> button beside the list
            This will add the project to the pod. The project will be highlighted to help differentiate it from the live projects.
            Note: This project cannot be re-added in the original pod but will remain there greyed out till the project is removed from the new pod.
          </p>
        </info>
      </step>
    </steps>
    <result>
      <p>A Plan is created or updated with deleted projects and per plan projects in the Capacity Planner.</p>
    </result>
  </taskbody>
</task>
