<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<task id="createPlan">
  <title>Plans</title>
  <taskbody>
    <context>
      <p>
        A plan within the Capacity Planner is the primary feature in the tool.
        This makes use of all the information entered in the other parts of the application
        as mentioned in the above prerequisites to allow the user to plan out the allocation
        of resources across the pods and how to make the best use of these resources. This involves
        assigning projects to various pods and selecting the predefined deployment types for these projects.
        The associated data-importer interactions also ensure that the actual real data taken from the clouds
        themselves is used here.
      </p>
      <p><b>Objective</b></p>
      <p>Use the Capacity Planner to create a plan for efficient cloud resource allocation</p>
      <p>
        <b>Outline</b>
        <ol>
          <li><xref href="#createPlan">Open the Create Plan View</xref></li>
          <li><xref href="#checkPods">Check the information in each Pod</xref></li>
          <li><xref href="#addProject">Add a Backlog Project to a Cloud Pod</xref></li>
          <li><xref href="#checkResources">Ensure Pod can handle the assigned resources</xref></li>
          <li><xref href="#updateCPUCR">Update CPU Contention Ratio</xref></li>
          <li><xref href="#updatePhysicalCapacity">Update Physical Capacity</xref></li>
          <li><xref href="#analyseAllocation">Analyse the Team Resource Allocation</xref></li>
        </ol>
      </p>
    </context>
    <prereq>
      <p>To create a plan successfully the user must have the following:</p>
      <ul>
        <li>Relevant Cloud Pods already created in the tool</li>
        <li>Relevant Projects already created in the tool</li>
        <li>Relevant Deployment Types already created in the tool</li>
        <li>Relevant Teams already created in the tool</li>
      </ul>
    </prereq>
    <steps>
      <step id="createPlan">
        <cmd>Open the Create Plan View</cmd>
        <info>
          <p>Click the <b>Create new plan</b> button from the plans page.</p>
        </info>
      </step>
      <step id="checkPods">
        <cmd>Check the information in each Pod</cmd>
        <info>
          <p>
            There will be a tab available for each Cloud Pod that is created with the Capacity Planner.
            These will contain all the information regarding the resource plans for that Pod - including
            the projects that are currently assigned to that Pod and, in turn, the deployment type.
            This then allows the tool to calculate the delta between the resources that the Cloud Pod has available
            and the resources required based on the project assigned to it.
          </p>
          <image href="/resources/images/plan/plan_pod_tabs.png" alt="Create Plan Tabs"/>
        </info>
      </step>
      <step id="addProject">
        <cmd>Add a Backlog Project to a Cloud Pod</cmd>
        <info>
          <p>Click the Backlog Projects <b>dropdown</b> menu as shown below</p>
          <image href="/resources/images/plan/add_project_dropdown.png" alt="Add Project"/>
          <p>
            When you click the above dropdown you are presented with all the available
            backlog project items. Select the required project and then click the add button.
            The project will be added to the plan, as well as updating the total resources required for the Pod overall.
          </p>
        </info>
      </step>
      <step id="checkResources">
        <cmd>Ensure Pod can handle the assigned resources</cmd>
        <info>
          <p>
            The overall Pod resource summary can be seen in the image below.
            This shows the Total Required(from the projects assigned in previous step) vs
            the Physical Capacity of the Pod and highlights where there are extra resources available
            as well as where there are not enough resources(like in the case of ENFS IOPS from the image below).
          </p>
          <image href="/resources/images/plan/resource_summary.png" alt="Resource Summary"/>
        </info>
      </step>
      <step id="updateCPUCR">
        <cmd>Update CPU Contention Ratio</cmd>
        <info>
          <p>
            The CPU Contention Ratio can be edited on this page to show what affect this would
            have on the vCPUs that are required by the associated projects. As you change it you
            can see the value highlighted in the below image change as this is now the new number of CPUs
            available based on the acceptable contention.
          </p>
          <image href="/resources/images/plan/cpu_contention.png" alt="CPU Contention"/>
        </info>
      </step>
      <step id="updatePhysicalCapacity">
        <cmd>Update Physical Capacity</cmd>
        <info>
          <p>
            All of the values in the Physical Capacity row are also editable. This will not
            update the actual values stored for the Cloud Pod. It can be used to trial what would happen
            if you added more ENFS IOPS for example to the Cloud Pod before making the real update.
            These ephemeral changes are useful in terms of planning out the cloud pods.
          </p>
          <image href="/resources/images/plan/update_capacity.png" alt="Physical Capacity"/>
        </info>
      </step>
      <step id="analyseAllocation">
        <cmd>Analyse the Team Resource Allocation</cmd>
        <info>
          <p>
            This section shows the resource allocation on a team level. This section shows the teams'
            resources across all the Cloud Pods so that the user can see how many resources a
            particular team are assigned regardless of the cloud these resources are on. This can be
            seen in the image below.
          </p>
          <image href="/resources/images/plan/team_resources.png" alt="Team Resources"/>
        </info>
      </step>
    </steps>
    <result>
      <p>A New Plan is created in the Capacity Planner.</p>
    </result>
  </taskbody>
</task>
